Guide to the Elizabeth Lochrie papers 1916-1979
Montana Historical Society Research Center
Elizabeth Lochrie papers
1916-1979
Montana Historical Society, Research Center Archives Archives 225 N. Roberts PO Box 201201 Helena MT 59620-1201 (406) 444-2681 mhslibrary@mt.gov
MC 291
Lochrie, Elizabeth.
17 linear feet of shelf space
Elizabeth Lochrie was a Butte, Montana, western artist. Collection (1916-1979) consists of correspondence, subject files, clippings, and memorabilia collected by Lochrie as source materials for her paintings.
Biographical Note:
Elizabeth Lochrie was born July 1, 1890, in Deer Lodge, Montana, to Frank and Mary Davey. Her father was an electrician for the City of Butte, and her mother was a musician, dietician and teacher. She had three younger brothers, Joe, Tom, and Clarence. She was educated in Deer Lodge and Butte, later attending the Pratt Institute, in Brooklyn, N.Y. for teacher training. Her impressive art education includes instruction from Wienold Reiss, Dorothy Pucinneli, and Victor Arnotoff.
Mrs. Lochrie's art career spans from the 1920s to the 1950s. Her patrons included the U.S. Treasury Department, the State of Montana, the Ford Motor Company, New York Life Insurance Company, and the First National Bank of Seattle. During 1924-1925 she painted eighteen children's murals for the Montana State Hospital at Galen, Montana. After 1931 she specialized in Native American portraits, particularly of Blackfoot tribal members, having produced more that a thousand water colors, oils, murals, and sculptures. In 1937 she won the Treasury Department's competition to paint a mural for the new Dillon post office with "News from the States" depicting the arrival of mail to that community in 1869. From 1937 to 1939 Lochrie also painted historic murals in the post offices at Burley and Saint Anthony, Idaho. She studied with Wienold Reiss at Glacier National Park and from 1936 to 1939 she was staff artist for the Great Northern Railroad in Glacier National Park. Her artistic honors also include arts show in New York City and at the prestigious Whitney Museum in Wyoming.
Elizabeth Lochrie's ties to the Native American tribes in Montana extended beyond her artwork. She frequently used the fees charged for her lectures to purchase clothing and other necessaries for needy members of Montana's tribes, especially the Blackfoot. She was adopted by the Blackfeet and given the name Netchitaki which translates to "Woman Alone on Her Way".
Elizabeth Davey married Arthur James Lochrie on June 14, 1913. The couple had two daughters, Betty Jane and Helena; and one son, Arthur James, Jr. Elizabeth Lochrie died in 1981.
This collection consists of biographical materials (1959-1970) including her resume; general correspondence (1932-1971) between Lochrie and her family, friends, fans, and people purchasing or commissioning her art work; diaries (1938, 1946-1967) these include traditional diaries and annotated calendars; financial records (1914-1968) includes scattered records of commissions, and daily household expenses; subject files (1914-1977) including newspaper clippings, correspondence, writings and research materials on various subjects relating primarily to art and Native Americans; speeches (1928-1953) primarily to service and women's groups regarding art and her study of Native Americans; writings (1940, 1947, undated) re Native American subjects primarily relating to people she painted; miscellany (1930-1979) including articles about Lochrie, art supply catalogs, guest books to her shows, and scrapbooks; clippings (1929-1970) from newspapers and magazines relating to art and artists, Native Americans, and Montana history.
by series
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition information available upon request
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the Montana Historical Society Archives catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search under these terms.
Artists--Montana.
Indians in art--Montana.
Mural painting and decoration--Montana--Dillon.
Mural painting and decoration--Montana--Galen.
Women artists--Montana.
Blackfeet Indians in art
Commercial art--Montana.
Portrait painters
Butte (Mont.)--Social life and customs.
Montana
Fine Arts
Native Americans
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Biographical Materials
  - Biographical writings and resume, 1959-1970 (Box-folder 1 / 1)
- General Correspondence
  - A (correspondents include Alamo Kiwanis Club; American Association of University Women; American Heritage Publishing; American Institute of Mining Auxiliary; American Federation of Arts;, Don Anderson; Ron Anderson; American Mother's Committee Inc.; Anaconda Woman's Club; Marguerite Arentzen; Hal Armstrong; Ruth Ashton; Thomas Ashworth; Mildred Azad), 1948-1970 (Box-folder 1 / 2)
  - American Indian Fund; American Indian Lore Association; and American Indian Hobbyist, 1954-1955 (Box-folder 1 / 3)
  - American Author and Artists (publishing house), 1947-1960 (Box-folder 1 / 4)
  - B (correspondents include Joe and Mary Back; Stanley Baker; Sally Barker, Marjorie Barton; Don Bartsch; William Baxter, Olive Beardsley; Ralph Beck; Robert Beck; Gordon Bennett, James Bennett; Big Timber Women's Club; Bird Neckles; Skyline Bill; William Biggerstaff; Jean Bishop; Margaret Black, Bobbitts; Marc Bourke; Betty Boyer; Evan Brandt; Marguerite Brisben; Cecile Blackboy; Christine Brundage; Harriett Brundage; George Brusin; David Burnham; Dale Burk; John Burke; William Burns; Chief Bull (Richard Banderville); Butte clubs (various), 1941-1976 (Box-folder 1 / 5)
  - Bear Medicine (Wilma and Marie), 1934-1965 (Box-folder 1 / 6)
  - Beta Sigman Pi, 1952-1965 (Box-folder 1 / 7)
  - Bull Child Family (Marie, George, Billie, Percy and John), 1932-1957 (Box-folder 1 / 8)
  - C (correspondents include Hughie Call; Geneva Calwell; Elizabeth Callaway; David Campbell; Connie Cannon; Paul Charlol; Mame Clark; Congregational Church of Butte; Steve Copulos; Cutbank Women's Club), 1940-1969 (Box-folder 1 / 9)
  - Butch and Helen Clarke (this couple handled booking, publicity and publication for Elizabeth for many years. First drafts of articles and information about shows found throughout this correspondence), 1951-1969 (Box-folder 1 / 10)
  - Belle Coates (re illustration's for proposed children's book by Coates), 1960-1961 (Box-folder 1 / 11)
  - Fredrick Conrad, 1937-1949 (Box-folder 1 / 12)
  - Jack Corrette (re establishment of Copper King Mansion as a museum), 1963 (Box-folder 1 / 13)
  - D (correspondents include Allan Denton; J. Maurice Dietrich; Mildred Dixon; Charles Donahoe; John Dooley; Margaret Driggs; Frank Ducharme; Verne Dusenberry), 1949-1969 (Box-folder 1 / 14)
  - Darvey Family (Ann and Jim), 1963-1966 (Box-folder 1 / 15)
  - Delta Kappa Gamma, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 1 / 16)
  - Jesse Duboc, 1944 (Box-folder 2 / 1)
  - E (Correspondents include Carl Eaton; Michele Egan; Gerald Edelston; Edith Eimerwau; Engineering and Mining Journal; Isabel Erickson; Lizbeth Eubank), 1941-1961 (Box-folder 2 / 2)
  - F (Correspondents include Dorothy Fear; Mary Merguson; Festival of Nations Committee; Grace Fillerup; Joseph Finkel; Bera Fitzgerald; Thelma Fitzgerald; Georgia Flint; Jim Flint; Ken Fowler; Scott Fries; Floy Fries; Maurice Frink; Sarah Fritjofson; Hans Fritzsche; T.R. Fritzsche; Sherrie Froelich; Harry Fulmer; Mary Frye), 1952-1969 (Box-folder 2 / 3)
  - Adele Faulkner (re Lloyd' s of Brentwood Interior Design, Arizona), 1948-1950 (Box-folder 2 / 4)
  - Federal School Inc. (re training in commercial art design via correspondence classes), 1931-1937 (Box-folder 2 / 5)
  - James T. Finlen (re bust done for Finlen Hotel lobby in Butte), 1954-1966 (Box-folder 2 / 6)
  - Ford Motor Company (Box-folder 2 / 7)
  - Samuel and Mary Ford (former Montana Governor), 1943-1950 (Box-folder 2 / 8)
  - G (Correspondents include Richard Gallup; Margaret Ganschew; Rev. Kent Gase; John Gilbert; Charlene Godtland; Douglas Gold; Mari Gold; Ivan Gore; Mildred Graeter; Great Falls Scouts Drum and Bugle Corps; Great Falls Tribune; Great Falls Women's Club; Evelyn Grinde), 1950-1968 (Box-folder 2 / 9)
  - Gaw Galleries (Helena business), 1952 (Box-folder 2 / 10)
  - Goldstone Family (Iris, W.L. and Nancy), 1949-1962 (Box-folder 2 / 11)
  - H (Correspondents include Katherine Hall; L.G. Hammer; Joe Hankins; Mrs. Ben Harding; Betty Harris; John Hay; Isabel Haynes; Helena Arts Council; Helena Exchange Club; Frank Henderson; Herbert Charles; Al Hibbard; Alma Higgins; Mary High; Hills Brothers Company; Hill Top Gallery in Butte; Stella Holmgron; John Holt; Joan Holter; Evelyn Huntley; G. Huygens), 1938-1970 (Box-folder 2 / 12)
  - Katie Home Gun, 1940-1953 (Box-folder 2 / 13)
  - I (correspondents include Neil Imes; International Directory of Arts), 1949-1965 (Box-folder 2 / 14)
  - Esther Rice Ingraham, 1944-1947 (Box-folder 2 / 15)
  - J (Correspondents include Alma Jenkins; Elda Johnson; Leah Johnson; Nell Johnson; Pam Johnson; Olga Johnson; Lula Jones; O' Neil Jones; Carl Jordan; Connie Jovich), 1938-1966 (Box-folder 2 / 16)
  - K (Correspondence include Betty Kanalz; L.S. Keller; Mrs. James Kello; D.M. Kelly; Martin Kelly; Myrtle Kelly; Kennedy Galleries; Joan Kirk; Cynthia Kissock; Judy Knapp; Gladys Knowles; Peggy Kopac; Joseph Kountz; Marilyn Kountz; Mabel Kyle), 1948-1965 (Box-folder 2 / 17)
  - L (Correspondents include Mabel Larabie; Mary LaRoque; Jay Larson; Nan Larson; Mike Lavis; Legallet Wool Company; Jessie Lincoln; J.C. Linduska; John Loewen; Harry Long; Harold Longmade; Melva Luxton), 1950-1964 (Box-folder 3 / 1)
  - Last Star Family (Theo and Cecile), 1946-1960 (Box-folder 3 / 2)
  - Lochrie Family (Arthur, Helen, A.J. and Elizabeth's grandchildren), 1936-1970 (Box-folder 3 / 3)
  - Ma-Moc (Correspondents include Marguerite Malone; Ella Mae; Louise Mannix; Marian White Arts and Crafts Club; Sam Mazzola; Mable McCraig; Florence McCrosky; Jack McLeod; Betty McMillan; Edna Mead; H.G. Merriam; Miles City Women's Club; Danette Miller; Helen Mitchell; Lorraine Mocassin), 1941-1967 (Box-folder 3 / 4)
  - Mont.-My (Correspondence include Montana Banker's Association; Montana Institute of Arts; Montana Farmer Stockman; Montana Press Women; Montana School of Mines; Montana State University; Museum of Plains Indian; Emma Mygatt), 1937-1967 (Box-folder 3 / 5)
  - Madonna Festival, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 3 / 6)
  - Maggie Many Hides, 1938-1941 (Box-folder 3 / 7)
  - Jim Masterson, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 3 / 8)
  - Montana Historical Society (re exhibits), 1952-1968 (Box-folder 3 / 9)
  - Mother of the Year (congratulations for Elizabeth being honored for Montana), 1960 (Box-folder 3 / 10)
  - N (Correspondents include Cecelia Nadler; Joy Nash; Laura Neurman; John Newman; Virginia Nichols; Andrew Nydam), 1941-1960 (Box-folder 3 / 11)
  - National Soap Sculpture Committee, 1933 (Box-folder 3 / 12)
  - Newton, Arthur (art gallery in New York), 1951-1963 (Box-folder 3 / 13)
  - O (Correspondents include David O'Brien; Oakland Biltmore Hotel; Blanche O'Nichols; Carole Orr; Marguerite Overland), 1940-1967 (Box-folder 3 / 14)
  - P (Correspondence includes Pacific Northwest Indian Center; Lawrence Packard; Ray Petterson; William Pond; Portland State College; Tamara Postel; Premium Service Company; Vincent Price Enterprises; Monte Proulz), 1948-1971 (Box-folder 3 / 15)
  - Doris Patten (re her work with Festival of Nations in Red Lodge), 1956-1960 (Box-folder 3 / 16)
  - PEO (memorial plaque to Blanche Walker), 1950 (Box-folder 3 / 17)
  - Courtney Proffitt, 1950 (Box-folder 3 / 18)
  - Thelma Hall Quast (re work of Quast as a journalist covering Crow tribe in Montana), 1953 (Box-folder 3 / 19)
  - R (Correspondents include Racine Art Foundry; Dolly Ralstone; Albert Randall; Virginia Rankin; S.F. Raynock; Mrs. Ricklef Reid; Mrs. J.K. Richardson; Dorothy Riskin; Phoebe Robinson; Will Rogers Jr.; Ruth Rome; Esther Ross; Audrey Roth; Roundup Women's Club; Richard Rubie; John Ruther; Edith Ryan), 1936-1964 (Box-folder 4 / 1)
  - Ravalli County Improvement Association, 1956 (Box-folder 4 / 2)
  - R.J. Reynolds Tobacco Company (re stock), 1956 (Box-folder 4 / 3)
  - Charles Rieger (for Marquette National Bank of Minneapolis), 1946-1953 (Box-folder 4 / 4)
  - Rotary Club (re trip to Laredo, Texas), 1940 (Box-folder 4 / 5)
  - S (Correspondents include Charles Scribner and Sons; Robert Seeley; W.P. Sherman; Irene Smith; Franz Stenzel), 1936-1969 (Box-folder 4 / 6)
  - Saturday Evening Post, 1939-1946 (Box-folder 4 / 7)
  - Marion Saunders (re illustrations for children's book "Indian Tales"), 1940-1948 (Box-folder 4 / 8)
  - Fred Shellenberg, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 4 / 9)
  - Rose Sklower (re Montana Federation of Women's Clubs), 1940-1942 (Box-folder 4 / 10)
  - Violet Sorrel Horse, 1935-1938 (Box-folder 4 / 11)
  - Jim Stingy, 1947-1956 (Box-folder 4 / 12)
  - T (Correspondents include Bess Tavesner; Ethel Thomas; J.K. Thomas; Jacques Townsend; Byrd Trego; Hazel Trisbee; Pete Tufts; Irv Turvey), 1941-1966 (Box-folder 4 / 13)
  - Thunder Bolt, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 4 / 14)
  - U-V (Correspondents include University of Montana School of Fine Arts; University of Wichita; Bill Ukrainetz; Jerome Vanderburg; Shirley Voyta), 1953-1968 (Box-folder 4 / 15)
  - W-Wh (Correspondents include Alfred Walmer; Doris Walstad; Mila Warn; Helen Watkins; Weasel Moccasin; Alvina Welliver; Western Montana College of Education; May White; Percy Whiting (for Dale Carnegie and Associates); Whitney Gallery of Western Art), 1938-1964 (Box-folder 4 / 16)
  - Who-Wu (Correspondents include Who's Who of American Women; Ruth Wiggins; H.F. Wilkening (exhibit in Spokane); Mrs. Carl Williams; Howard Williams; Minnie Williams; Rachel Williams; Ruth Williams; Russell Williams; Claire Wilson; Elizabeth Wilson; Wind River Valley Artist's Guild; Isabell Wolfe; Kathryn Wright; Jack Wryn; Hermann Wunderlich (for Kennedy Galleries in New York), 1942-1968 (Box-folder 4 / 17)
  - Burton K. Wheeler, 1943 (Box-folder 4 / 18)
  - Wolf Robe family (Cecilia, Mary, Betty of Browning, Montana), 1932-1951 (Box-folder 4 / 19)
  - Y-Z (Correspondents include Clara Yaeger (for Laredo, Texas library; Yellowstone Gallery; Zesbaugh's Art Store (Minneapolis); Young Men's Christian Association (Butte); Necky Yolk; Zellah Yegen (Billings); Ralph Zopfi), 1949-1967 (Box-folder 4 / 20)
  - Student letters (letters from Montana students requesting information from Elizabeth Lochrie about her work or thanking her for coming to their classrooms), 1941, 1951-1954 (Box-folder 5 / 1)
  - Unidentified or partial letters (primarily relating to painting orders and fan mail), 1936-1970, undated (Box-folder 5 / 2-3)
- Diaries
  - "9th Summer to Study My Beloved Indians", 1938 (Box-folder 5 / 4)
  - Diaries and date books (includes scattered entries recording art exhibits and sales), 1946-1967 (Box-folder 5 / 5-9)
- Financial Records
  - Commission records (includes account records for Jean Linduska, G.A. Merchant; Gaw Gallery, and Raymond's), 1947-1963 (Box-folder 5 / 10-11)
  - Commission records (includes general sales accounts), 1941-1968 (Box-folder 6 / 1-2)
  - Frame orders, 1951, undated (Box-folder 6 / 3)
  - Household accounts, 1914-1929 (Box-folder 6 / 4)
- Subject Files
  - All American Indian Days (festival in Sheridan, Wyoming in which Elizabeth Lochrie participated), 1954-1967 (Box-folder 6 / 5-8)
  - All American Indian Days, Miss Indian America Contest (festival in Sheridan, Wyoming in which Elizabeth Lochrie participated as a judge), 1954-1957 (Box-folder 6 / 9-11)
  - All American Indian Days, Miss Indian America Contest (festival in Sheridan, Wyoming, in which Elizabeth Lochrie participated as a judge), 1959-1973 (Box-folder 7 / 1-6)
  - Art shows (in-state and across the country), 1962-1967 (Box-folder 8 / 1)
  - Anthropology, 1943 (Box-folder 8 / 2)
  - Blackfeet Indians (research on individuals she painted), undated (Box-folder 8 / 3)
  - Federal School of Commercial Design (includes correspondence, sketches, workbooks and miscellany) [Oversized Material: Oversized Box 1], 1926 (Box-folder 8 / 4-11)
  - Federal School of Commercial Design (includes correspondence, sketches, workbooks and miscellany) [Oversized Material: Oversized Box 1], 1926 (Box-folder 9 / 1-5)
  - Gallop, New Mexico (includes sketches and notes from trip she took), 1943 (Box-folder 9 / 6)
  - Houston, Texas (includes sketches and notes from trip she took), 1956 (Box-folder 9 / 7)
  - Image resource files (images taken from commercial advertisements, magazines, photographs, calendars, etc. relating to various topics used by artist as resource for her own works--subjects include animals, buildings, children, landscapes, western ranch images), 1956 (Box-folder OVBX / 2-7)
  - Mexico (includes sketches and notes from trip she took), undated (Box-folder 9 / 8)
  - Montana writers (research on writers of interest to Mrs. Lochrie), 1914-1936, undated (Box-folder 9 / 9)
  - Mother of the Year (national competition for which Mrs. Lochrie was nominated for Montana in 1960), 1960, 1977 (Box-folder 10 / 1-2)
  - Native American Cradle (Blackfeet word is Ka-pi-ma-ne), 1930 (Box-folder 10 / 3)
  - Native American names (includes place names) See also Oversize: box 16, 1950, 1974, undated (Box-folder 10 / 4)
  - Newton Gallery Exhibit (New York), 1951 (Box-folder 10 / 5)
  - Eugene Perry (includes sketches for "Zig and Zog" a children's book), 1951 (Box-folder 10 / 6)
  - Rainbow Hotel (Great Falls) includes sketches for advertisement, undated (Box-folder 10 / 7)
  - Jessie Schultz (re illustrations for her children's books "Let's Play Indian" and "The Squirrel and the Rabbit". No sketches included), undated (Box-folder 10 / 8-9)
  - Ida Stendels (re Montana Writer's and Artists Project and plans to include Elizabeth Lochrie in the publication], 1940 (Box-folder 10 / 10)
  - Sun Dance, 1953, undated (Box-folder 10 / 11)
  - Writer's and Illustrator's Exchange (includes sketches), 1916, undated (Box-folder 10 / 12)
- Speeches
  - Murals (includes notes on pioneer art, art in Montana, American art, miniature art), 1928, undated (Box-folder 10 / 13)
  - Art (re American art and artists, illustrations, and Mother's Day art], 1938-1945 (Box-folder 10 / 14)
  - "The Emergence of Mothers", undated (Box-folder 11 / 1)
  - "Dr. Caroline McGill" given to the Homer Club of Butte, 1953 (Box-folder 11 / 2)
  - "Montana Indians" (given to Butte Rotary Club), 1945 (Box-folder 11 / 3)
- Writings
  - Biographies of Native Americans she painted (includes Cecile Bear Medicine, Chief Dewey Beard, Chief Bird Rattler, George Bull Child, Chief Crazy Horse, John Clarke, Curley, Chief Eagle Child, Agat Dillon Finley, Mrs. Lydia Four Paws, Mary Kipp, Chief Joseph, Mountain Chief, Julian Little Plume, John Eagle-Calf, Theodore Last-Star, Thomas Old Coyote, Johnny Pilco, Captain John Smith, Chief Turtle, Chief Yellow Robe), undated (Box-folder 11 / 4)
  - "Blackfeet Indian Tee-Pee Tales", 1947 (Box-folder 11 / 5-17)
  - "Colstrip Study" and "Montana is Artists Paradise", 1940, undated (Box-folder 11 / 18)
  - Collected writings of Elizabeth Lochrie and Marion Russell re: Sun Dances at Crow Agency, St. Xavier, Pryor, Busby, Lame Deer and Fort Washakie, Wyoming (includes scattered photographs), 1946-1963 (Box-folder 11 / 19)
- Miscellany
  - Application materials for art exhibits, competitions, juried shows (national and regional events), 1940-1950, undated (Box-folder 11 / 20)
  - Articles about Elizabeth Lochrie (primarily printed in art magazines), 1950-1970 (Box-folder 12 / 1)
  - Autographs (from Debbie Reynolds, Lucille Ball, Danny Thomas, Charles Lindbergh, Jack Benny) [RESTRICTED], undated (Box-folder 12 / 2)
  - Lists of cards and gifts (both received and given), 1949-1975 (Box-folder 12 / 3)
  - Cards, invitations and post cards [Oversized Material: Oversize Box 10], 1950-1979 (Box-folder 12 / 4-5)
  - Catalogs, art supplies, undated (Box-folder 12 / 6-7)
  - Children's books (notes from various books with ideas for illustrations), undated (Box-folder 12 / 8)
  - Essay by Thomas Campbell re his mother (sent to Elizabeth Lochrie with regards), 1935 (Box-folder 13 / 1)
  - Exhibit brochures (from various Lochrie Exhibits), 1937-1970 (Box-folder 13 / 2)
  - Guest book from exhibit in Deer Lodge, 1970 (Box-folder 13 / 3)
  - Guest Book (Junior League in Butte), 1954 (Box-folder 13 / 4)
  - Index of Native American terms and names (primarily relating to Crow and Blackfeet languages), undated (Box-folder OVBX / 8)
  - List of books read, 1952 (Box-folder 13 / 5)
  - Montana History notes, 1953, undated (Box-folder 13 / 7)
  - List of Montana artists, undated (Box-folder 13 / 6)
  - Outdoor advertising (notes on sign sizing etc.), undated (Box-folder 13 / 8)
  - Publications regarding Native Americans (primarily federal publications used by Lochrie for research), 1950-1979 (Box-folder 13 / 9)
  - Scrapbooks (re art shows, Butte history, family history, and travel), 1950-1979 (Box-folder OVBX / 9-10)
  - Sketches and notes (various project and topics) [Oversized Material: Oversize Box 11], 1953, 1965, undated (Box-folder 13 / 11)
- Clippings
  - Art and artists, 1929-1964 (Box-folder 14 / 1)
  - Blackfeet Indians, 1930-1970 (Box-folder 14 / 2-6)
  - Buffalo, 1960 (Box-folder 14 / 7)
  - Butte, 1934-1940, undated (Box-folder 14 / 8)
  - Cheyenne Indians, 1962-1971 (Box-folder 14 / 9)
  - Crow Indians, 1934-1961 (Box-folder 14 / 10)
  - Custer Battlefield, 1953 (Box-folder 15 / 1)
  - Flathead Indians, undated (Box-folder 15 / 2)
  - Fort Belknap, undated (Box-folder 15 / 3)
  - Fort Shaw Indian Reservation, 1961 (Box-folder 15 / 4)
  - Glasgow, 1937 (Box-folder 15 / 5)
  - Indian Days Celebrations (in Browning, Montana), 1957-1974 (Box-folder 15 / 6)
  - Lewis and Clark (primarily regarding celebrations), 1955 (Box-folder 15 / 7)
  - Elizabeth Lochrie (mostly Montana articles regarding her art shows), 1955 (Box-folder 15 / 8)
  - Caroline McGill (primarily about Museum of the Rockies bequest), 1967 (Box-folder 15 / 9)
  - Montana History (various topics), 1930-1940s, undated (Box-folder 15 / 10)
  - Native Americans (non-Montana tribes), 1930-1950s (Box-folder 15 / 11)
  - Nez Perce, 1950s (Box-folder 15 / 12)
  - Sun Dance, 1947, undated (Box-folder 15 / 13)
  - Virginia City (Montana), 1955, undated (Box-folder 15 / 14)